Guide to the Department of Classics, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Classics, Yale University, records
1913-1990
RU 419
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.25
The records consist of minutes, correspondence, reports, and personnel files documenting personnel, teaching appointments, curriculum, the American Numismatic Society, and the Board of Permanent Officers of the Yale Department of Classics.
Yale University. Department of Classics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Classics, 1931-2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, correspondence, reports, and personnel files documenting personnel, teaching appointments, curriculum, the American Numismatic Society, and the Board of Permanent Officers of the Yale Department of Classics.
Classical literature -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; American Numismatic Society; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Classics
- Minutes of faculty meetings, 1913-1926; Accession 1931-A-001
  - Minutes of faculty meetings, 1913-1926 (Box 1)
- Minutes of meetings of the permanent officers, 1945-1958; Accession 1984-A-013
  - Meeting minutes of the permanent officers, 1945-1958 (Box 1)
- Records, 1931-1971; Accession 1988-A-028
  - Administrative Records
    - Actions of Department Meetings, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual Department Reports and President's Report, 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Departmental Correspondence, 1933-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Department Meeting Minutes and Requirements for Doctorate Degress, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Department Meetings - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Reports of Committees, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Minutes of Department Meetings
    - Teaching Program and Assignments, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Numismatic Society Correspondence
    - Bellinger-Authors, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Printers, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yale Classical Studies Records
    - Correspondence, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Accounts, estimates, statements, correspondence, 1944-1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Director of Graduate Studies, 1931-1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous from files
    - List of Coins from Curium and from Apollo, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - A Paper on Professor James Luce Kingsley read before the Yale Classical Club, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - University of North Carolina, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Applications and Inquiries
    - Re: Departmental Teaching Positions at Yale, 1932-1943 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Re: Departmental Teaching Positions at Yale, 1942-1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Re: Departmental Teaching Positions at Yale, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Personal Correspondence with Recommendations
    - Brown, Frank E., 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Harmon, Austin Morris, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Re: Positions-Teachings
    - Welles, C. Bradford, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - American Numismatic Society Correspondence
  - Personnel Files [restricted 75 years from year individual left Yale]
    - Research Assistants and Fellows, 1933-1943 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Research Assistants, Fellows, and Other Employees, 1944-1957 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Teaching Appointments
    - Formal Notices and Recommendations, 1931-1954 (Box 4, Folder 56 - 57)
    - Formal Notices and Reqommendations, 1944-1958 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Teaching Positions Outside Yale Inquiries and Recommendations, 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Teaching Positions Outside Yale Inquiries and Recommendations, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 60 - 61)
    - Teaching Positions Outside Yale Inquiries and Recommendations, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 62 - 63)
    - Teaching Positions Outside Yale Inquiries and Recommendations, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Position Vacancies Outside Yale, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 65 - 66)
  - Miscellaneous - Department Files
    - Classical Club of Yale University, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Rostovtzeff-Welles Library - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Faculty records, 1930-1990; Accession 2008-A-079
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2066
  - Little, A.M.G., 1930-1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)